# **Ankit Tripathi**

I am a passionate programmer and tech enthusiast. I have 2 years of experience as a Full-Stack Developer and 8 months of internship experience. I have experience with REST APIs, micro-services and AWS cloud. My short term goal is to work on and design extremely scalable and reliable systems, hence I am looking forward to working in a fast paced environment where I can learn new things everyday.

**EXPERIENCE** 

# Barclays Bank, Pune — Full Stack Developer, BA3

Aug 2019 - PRESENT

Works on designing, creating, consuming and documenting REST APIs with complex business logic using Spring Boot following the TDD approach and creating UI using React/AngularJS then deploying these components on a microservice architecture. Works on performing peer to peer code reviews and participates in business, analysis and triage calls to provide technical input.

# **Germin8 Solutions,** Mumbai — *Intern Developer*

June 2018 - Feb 2019

Worked on Stream Processing using Kafka on Spring Boot and integrating third party APIs into an Event Driven System . Developed a simple POC for an Alexa chatbot. Got exposure to AWS S3 and Apache Cassandra.

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

### **KJSCE CodeCell**, Mumbai — Tech Team Member

May 2017 - May 2018

A volunteer committee focused on improving coding culture at our college. Speaker in various workshops, including Python, C++ STL, Git, Modular Programming, etc. Helped in organising KJSCE Hackathon, KJSCE CodeSpree (Programming Contest) and BlockChain Workshop.

Azad Compound, Ganesh Nagar, Kandivali (W), Mumbai - 400067 (+91) 7506155808 tripathiankit22@gmail.com

Links: <u>GitHub</u>, <u>CodeChef</u>, <u>LinkedIn</u>, <u>Portfolio</u>

#### **SKILLS**

Spring Boot/Java - Expert

Django/Python - Expert

Node.JS - Intermediate

C/C++ - Intermediate

DS and Algorithms - Expert

Git - Expert

RAML - Expert

Jenkins - Intermediate

Linux and Bash Scripting -Intermediate

Android Development -Intermediate

ReactJS - Expert

**AngularJS** - Intermediate

Docker - Intermediate

Kafka - Intermediate

Cassandra - Beginner

**Redis** - Intermediate

AWS - Intermediate

**HDFS** - Beginner

**gRPC** - Beginner

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Most Improved Colleague Award - Barclays Channels Awards - 2020, Received recognition for being a quick

#### **EDUCATION**

# **KJ Somaiya College of Engineering,** Mumbai — B. Tech

June 2015 - June 2019 - 7.8 CGPA

# Shri T.P. Bhatia Jr. College, Mumbai — HSC

June 2013 - June 2015 - 81.23%

## S. V. N. English School, Mumbai — SSC

June 2003 - June 2013 - 83.45%

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# **Lip Reading in the Wild** — A P.O.C. of performing word recognition using spatio–temporal CNN.

Trained a spatio-temporal CNN model on AWS EC2 Instance, and demonstrated the working of the model by performing word recognition using a python program on Tensorflow and Keras libraries. Published a paper in Springer Publication on this topic.

# **TripSharr** — An Android App that lets you record your trips, create an itinerary and share it.

Worked in a group of 5. Used CodeIgniter(PHP) in backend and Android App as frontend. It was part of a 1 month long App Development Marathon and we won the 2<sup>nd</sup> price.

# **Vahaan** — A prototype to pay tolls and notification of PUC renewals online.

Worked in a group of 3 in a 1-day Hackathon. Used Django in Backend and Frontend was Bootstrap.

Code: https://github.com/Chaitya62/Vahaan

# **FaceApp** — A chat application based on NodeJS.

Worked along with a friend in creating a simple chat application based on Node.js. Used handlebars to render UI templates and serve them directly through the Node Server.

Code: https://github.com/Ankit-22/faceapp

#### learner.

Honourable Mention - ACM ICPC Regionals, Being the top team (of 3) in our college in ACM ICPC Online Qualifiers qualified for Amritapuri Regionals, Kerala - 2018

1st Runner Up, Riddl App Development Marathon Finished second in a 1 month long, Inter-College App Development Marathon.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Rest API (Intermediate)
Certificate, Hackerrank <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/">https://www.hackerrank.com/</a>
/certificates/c53aebd812d1

Data Structures and Algorithms - Udemy - It is a course to learn basic data structures and algorithms concepts https://www.udemy.com/cert

https://www.udemy.com/cert ificate/UC-EKR9DVLR/

RHEL Technical Overview –
An official course made by
RHEL to understand basic
concepts of Linux.
<a href="https://www.udemy.com/cert">https://www.udemy.com/cert</a>
ificate/UC-8QTYDAYQ/

### **INTERESTS**

Chess, Cricket, Science & Technology, Machine Learning, Youtube

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Marathi, Bhojpuri.